Unlock the secret.
Enigma is a mystery, drama, thriller film directed by Michael Apted.
The story of the WWII project to crack the code behind the Enigma machine, used
by the Germans to encrypt messages sent to their submarines.
Tom Jericho, played by Dougray Scott.
Hester Wallace, played by Kate Winslet.
Claire Romilly, played by Saffron Burrows.
Mr. Wigram, played by Jeremy Northam.
Puck, played by Nikolaj Coster-Waldau.
Logie, played by Tom Hollander.
Enigma is a 2001 espionage thriller film directed by
Michael Apted from a screenplay by Tom Stoppard.
The script was adapted from the 1995 novel Enigma by Robert Harris, about the
Enigma codebreakers of Bletchley Park in the Second World War.
Although the story is highly fictionalised, the process of encrypting German messages during World War II and decrypting
them with the Enigma is discussed in detail, and the historical event of the Katyn massacre is highlighted.
It was the last film scored by John Barry.
The film explores themes of friendship, submarine, female
lover, world war ii, radio transmission.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.